<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
	<string id="ls_header">
		<text>S.T.A.L.K.E.R. Anomaly 1.5.3</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_number">
		<text>#</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_0">
		<text>Do you know the person standing behind you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_1">
		<text>"Is it true?" "Yes. There was some sort of critical failure and radiation has spread all around; Pripyat is being evacuated. Keep this between ourselves." The Director hung up the phone and leaned back in his chair, deep in thought. Perhaps this was just the opportunity his project needed. He picked up the phone and began to dial.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_2">
		<text>It didn't go to plan. I was on the ground clutching my abdomen and cursing the little lead slug that was twisting around in there. Even in my agony, I grimaced with irony. "They had a sniper in that tower. Those crafty bastards." I heard footsteps and looked up to a gun barrel and the soulless eyes of a gas mask behind them. Then a bang.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_3">
		<text>Now that I was safe, I decided to take a breather and check the goods in my pack: three Flashes, a Fireball, some sort of greenish Shell, thirteen anomalous strands and a clay sphere that could levitate. I smiled to myself and zipped up the pack - first good day in months!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_4">
		<text>That seedy bastard was grinning at me over the table - he knew that I had already given in. "You better come through for me, I want a ticket out of here and no tricks." He assured me and passed me another glass. So I told him everything. Next morning, the entire garrison was killed to a man.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_5">
		<text>It wasn't long before we got held up by bandits. I had heard of these ones before and I had a bad feeling - these rapists and murderers wouldn't be content with just our stuff. As I was trying to come up with a plan, the stalker next to me drew a gun and killed them before they could react. He faded into the night, leaving us standing there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_6">
		<text>"Results?" "We have a co-efficient of fourty-seven point... five, Professor." The Professor smiled and removed his hearing protection, gazing on the giant machine and the smoking hole with admiration. Finally stabilized... I'd like to see armor plating that can withstand this! The assistant went up to the control panel and the electric hum gradually died away.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_7">
		<text>The sortie was careful to stay well away from the marked regions inside of the fenced area. There were three choppers and they all were making use of night-vision optics. "Movement! Towards the border from bearing 275!" The gunner swiveled over and saw the mark - some sort of bizarre animal pack. The gun pods opened up.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_8">
		<text>"Finally, to give over my physical body to the Zone in battle and to let my consciousness dissolve within." The only light in the cave was a reddish fire. "Good", said the one called Chernobog. "Now, for the last." The initiate was grabbed from behind by four strong arms and a needle was inserted into the neck. As his senses dulled, a cloudy veil passed over him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_9">
		<text>I had lain this way for hours, but my crosshair never moved from his head. "C'mon, why wait?" I thought impatiently. I didn't have much reason to complain - this job couldn't be easier, just had to wait for the confirmation. The target looked around and then pulled out the small encoder I was waiting for. After a moment of sympathy, I squeezed the trigger.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_10">
		<text>The exit was just ahead. Dragging my bleeding leg through the tunnel passage, I listened for the sounds that I dreaded coming up behind. On the upside, I had the object clutched safe in my arm. As I turned the last corner, my heart sank. The door was completely blocked - a cave-in. Throwing my treasure to the floor, I sunk to my knees and accepted my fate.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_11">
		<text>The novice watched as his mentor crouched down, all the way to the ground, to slide under the pulsating spot above. It had been fifteen minutes since he had entered, but he was almost near the end. After a couple tentative bolt throws, he slowly reached out his hand to the glowing shape. He grasped it and placed it in the jar. The novice grinned in admiration.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_12">
		<text>Another dreary day at the border posting. Oranovsky noticed that many more seemed to be leaving than entering, in contrast to the past busy weeks of new operations. He asked a passing corporal, who simply said, "We have angered the Zone. There's nothing but failure for us there." Gloomily, he trudged past.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_13">
		<text>It was a beautiful morning in Sochi, but the grimy windows of the trashy bar blocked it out. The two men had just stopped talking and waited for the third to answer. Gritsenko slowly said, after a long drag at the cigarette: "Very well, I'll take a look at your little circus. I want half of the money now as well as a full set-up on site." They proposed a toast.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_14">
		<text>The view from the top of the tower was almost pretty, as long as you forgot where you were. The scout took another look at the eastern treeline and stopped short on some shadows just shy of the clearing. Something emerged on to the plain and into the view of his binoculars. Into the radio he hurriedly whispered, "It's starting, looks like more than we thought."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_15">
		<text>"And you", said Sultan, "thought no one would notice?" The prisoner was silent, which only inflamed Sultan's temper. He signaled the man with the steel bar and the beating began. Periodically, he would stop to let the captive talk, but he never did. Soon, Sultan forgot his anger and was impressed. Maybe this man was better as a servant than an enemy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_16">
		<text>There were three of them crawling through the field: Anton, Kostya and the guide. Darkness had fallen a half hour ago and they had just crawled under the hole in the fence. Still, it was a hundred meters or more to the safety of the trees. Suddenly, a flare lit up the land with red. "Just go, run!", shouted the guide as they sprang to their feet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_17">
		<text>I didn't want to think about the water I was immersed in - honestly, I'd be happy enough to live through the next 24 hours, screw the cancer. My mask was water-tight, so I was able to look up from the bottom of the pool to the surface where my drinking straw pulled air. I tensed as a shadow passed by - they were still searching for me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_18">
		<text>Garik allowed himself a yawn, but he never took his eyes off from the strange stalker standing at the table in the corner. Barkeep was still making inquisitive faces to his bouncer, but neither of them could figure out the silent customer. Suddenly, the stalker started making towards the door, but he collapsed after a step. He was in a coma and the doc was stumped.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_19">
		<text>The mercenary woke up in the darkness with a cry, looking for his gun. Then, as he saw his surroundings, he remembered where he was, even though that wasn't much of a comfort. "Get a fucking grip", he muttered. He had the nightmare again - it followed him even in here. Taking an empty bottle of whiskey, he flung it across the room where it shattered.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_20">
		<text>The blazing campfire shot up defiantly into the black night sky and the three wayfarers were all glad of its comfort. They didn't have any more stories to tell and the guitar was busted, so they just sat there, vaguely listening. They felt a sense of danger, but removed danger, like gunshots over the horizon. One by one, they drifted off to sleep.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_21">
		<text>The sun was rising on Rostok as the private waited around for his watch to be relieved. The sun mounted the grey concrete and rusty towers of the old plant and, to his surprise, the private found his eyes full of tears. When was the last time he had seen a sunrise? It must have been all those years ago, back when life seemed much more small and good. He bowed his head.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_22">
		<text>With a scraping noise, the massive door swung open on its rusty hinges; it had been decades since this door was opened. The half-dozen Spetsnaz operators trained their weapons on the utterly black passageway just revealed and waited for orders. After a pause, a feral bellow issued from somewhere deep inside the installation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_23">
		<text>"There have been many rumors going around, but I would like to reiterate that they are rumors only." The Minister of the Interior was speaking to a throng of jostling reporters; one of them asked: "So the reports of military action within the Exclusion Zone are false?" "They are completely out of proportion, there only exists a minor policing situation."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_24">
		<text>After several minutes, the old man sitting on the stool began to speak, "Expect a series of harsh emissions in two days. I also can see a push by the Monolith - they will redouble their attack on Limansk." The prophet fell silent - there would be no more news. The visitors exchanged significant looks and prepared to leave - the predictions had yet to fail.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_25">
		<text>As the young man prepared to leave the room, Forester suddenly grabbed his arm and gripped. "Wait", he hissed. The young stalker stopped breathing as a distortion of pain and fear appeared on the old ranger's face. After three tense minutes, he relaxed and withdrew his arm. "Go now, my son. The danger has passed."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_26">
		<text>"Now, you just go to bed and no more jumping about." Mr. Howell left his daughter's room and stopped in his tracks by his window; his jaw dropped. From the window of his flat, over the lights of London, a dazzling glow lit up the eastern sky. He exhaled - not a nuke, he thought. He didn't want Jordan to see this. He dialed 999, but all lines were engaged. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_27">
		<text>I held up both hands, although it was difficult from my position on the ground. The group of men surrounded me, most of them were pointing guns. I had ditched my shooter and my insignia, but it was still obvious what I was. As I awaited judgment I heard, "Wait!" An older stalker pushed into the circle and held out his hand to me. "My name's Fanatic... and who might you be?"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_28">
		<text>After I tied my shoes I did one last check: coat, food, some money, a pair of felt boots and the old hunting rifle. As I stepped out the door, thin arms clasped me from behind. "Please don't, you won't come back." I turned around and gathered Katya's hands within mine. "I will. And everything will be better." That's the last thing I said to her.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_29">
		<text>Ivar was called "The Tractor" because he was big, strong and not very subtle. He walked right up to the lounging, hooded stalker in the Bar and gave him a neat one in the face. Out of respect to the proprietor, he dragged the skinny man out of the Bar and flung him on the ground. "It was you!" he growled. Time to get answers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_30">
		<text>I adjusted the oxygen tank on my back and looked up at the huge column of radioactive smoke pouring out of the reactor. Suddenly, my rubberized suit and stifling mask didn't seem heavy enough. I trudged on as a firetruck raced past and I watched a dust cloud rise into the air. I hadn't even heard of a Sievert at that time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_31">
		<text>This was taking way too long. The only light in the room was a dirty fluorescent one blinking on the floor, which didn't make it easy to find the document I was seeking. I had just finished up the second file cabinet - no luck. As I moved onto the third, I heard a scuffling sound in the hall outside. In a panic, I ran over to the door and blocked it with a desk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_32">
		<text>On top of the grainy feed of the night vision, the pouring rain reduced visibility down to almost nothing. The storm seemed to be intensifying and we were still out in the middle of wind-swept nowhere in the black of night. I turned back to Roman but he was nowhere to be seen. Hiding wasn't an option - it was run or die.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_33">
		<text>I would go down to Sidorovich's bunker soon, but for the moment I just felt like standing in the middle of the lane, looking into the deep night sky resplendent with stars. My second night in the Zone! I realized that Glasgow had never seemed so far away until this very moment. I half-wondered if I would ever see it again... but it was time to get my payment.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_34">
		<text>The set day had come, and the carefully selected company issued from the military camp. Captain Tachenko led his squad out into the unmapped territory (he himself knew it well) and smashed their communications gear. They would be written off as lost. Tachenko looked at Kosmach and they understood one another. It was time to fight the Zone on their own terms.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_35">
		<text>Another late night at the depot, and Bondarov was getting all together fed-up with the endless paperwork blurring in front of his eyes. "What I can't understand", he said to Nikolai, "is the massive rate of equipment attrition in this sector. Why in the hell do they need two massive shipments a month?" He sighed and looked up at the logistics map: SECTOR 17, CHERNOBYL.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_36">
		<text>This was the one risky job that the smuggler accepted - it was just too good to pass up. He was piloting a little barge in the dead of night over the dark water and saw the lighted pier ahead. He knew it would be over for him if he was caught, but there was no higher-paying gun-running in the world - he didn't even have to meet with them! The sign said: "Pripyat River Port".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_37">
		<text>After the lights were turned on, the squad commander radioed back on the encrypted channel, "This is Thrush's group in section 7, sub-level 5. We've found another supply room with a large amount of munitions and various equipment. All local resistance has been neutralized. Glory to the Monolith!"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_38">
		<text>The sweat was running down my face and I could hardly stand; the assault on the Barrier had kept up for more than an hour. First, we were surprised by a stampede of pissed-off hogs and then a general release of all of the Zone's genetic refuse. After, when we were catching our breath, They came. By now, there were few of us left and little hope for any more. Where has Gatekeeper gone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_39">
		<text>The truck with only one headlight working rolled up to the decrepit, but not deserted, station and stopped. A stream of men issued from the doorway and they were all carrying bodies; they didn't bother to check which ones were still useful and which were completely dead, they just piled them in. The driver, with unseeing glazed eyes, drove off.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_40">
		<text>Once you get past the scaly hide, it's much easier. After rolling the massive corpse over with my leg, I made a few deep incisions and started pulling out the cuts that looked safe to eat. Even avoiding the tumors, most of the meat was unpleasant. Well, fine. I had business up here and the road to the Skadovsk was none too friendly these days.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_41">
		<text>The sirens had stopped and that was a bad sign. The sky was erupting in orange and purple lightning. The bunker was only a dozen steps away, but Ilya's dead-weight on my wounded shoulder was crushing and my feet stumbled. As the pulsating wave swept over the horizon, I dumped him inside the bunker and shut the door. I mumbled a little prayer of gratitude and passed out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_42">
		<text>The junior assistant tumbled down the stairs and burst into the head office. "Comrade Professor! They're ordering a complete evacuation, apparently a reactor failure." The man sitting behind the desk coldly considered the situation and then replied, "Continue the work, comrade. We are not abandoning this facility. Send in the security chief." The assistant sprinted from the room.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_43">
		<text>After a long minute of staring at the bizarre object, Grant asked the man, "What is it?" "That's not my business," he answered gruffly. "You wanted your expensive specimen and here it is. Where's the money?" Grant pointed him to the next room and then closed the door to the lab. Looking back to the rare object, he realized he had no idea where to begin.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_44">
		<text>The blindfolded man was shoved into the dark room and the door slammed behind him. The sedation was wearing off and the man felt fear. Even before he ripped his blindfold away, he knew there was something else in the room. A white-hot spike plunged into his brain and he knew no more. "XI-53 terminated subject 451J within seconds. High aggression and potent telekinetics observed."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_45">
		<text>"So he's a problem?" Sidorovich wanted this matter decided on, he had other things to do. "Yes", said the northerner, "we're almost positive that he's working for the SSU." Sidorovich paused a second for effect and said, "Well, we can't be too careful. You can get rid of him." Little did they know, the Major had just been extracted via helicopter on the previous day.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_46">
		<text>Navigator was angry and, probably, a bit frightened. He hurled his pack to the floor and said, "We have to make up the time tomorrow, or we're done for." He settled down to sleep as I looked around the place. There would be no fire - too dangerous. I heard the howling from the far moon-lit plains. It would be a long night.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_47">
		<text>More ground units, more air patrols and even a BTR they managed to drag across the swamps - not good. I'm the only one in the entire sector, so I have to transmit the co-ordinates extremely cautiously. Suddenly, a soldier walks up to my hiding place - so close I could touch his boot. Then he moves on. How long until Lebedev can send relief? I'm nearly out of water...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_48">
		<text>Podychev was having severe second doubts when he saw his stasis chamber and he froze in place. After a while, Professor Chubko came in and assured him, "We talked about this, remember? There will be no pain, and after, there will be nothing that can harm you." Chubko guided him by the hand, but he was still terrified. He lowered himself into the tube and was sealed in.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_49">
		<text>I looked down at the fallen Duty man. His breathing was shallow and fitful, and his armor was rent and studded with impact marks. "Well?", said Messer, "Do we finish him?" I took a medpack and some water out of my bag and laid them at his side. Then I gave the signal to move on. Messer ran up to my side. "Lukash will be pissed if he hears." I didn't care, I had enough killing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_50">
		<text>I sat at the desk and Kuznetsov stood over me. "Sign it," he commanded. I looked down at the report - a lie. But we both knew I didn't have much of a choice. As I started writing I could feel him lean back and resume his informal air. "CASUALTY CERTIFICATE: Major Khaletskiy - MIA, unknown fate"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_51">
		<text>The cables detached and the massive helicopters flew off, glad to be rid of their burden. The concrete research bunker squatted heavily in its new position; there was much work to be done, but the surrounding area had to first be secured. The military security team had been there for days, but hostile activity from the swamp started up again as soon as the lab was dropped.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_52">
		<text>Kalancha held his breath as the program opened up and the radio signals came in. It worked! Here, upon the computer monitor, was an entire sensor array feeding in various measurements from the whole swamp. Kalancha could now monitor both anomaly changes and physical movement, be it human or otherwise. The smiling technicians came in - time for a toast!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_53">
		<text>I crawled up onto the back of the thing and tried to hold it down, but even with a shattered arm it was immensely strong. The muscular legs were battering away as I attempted to get my hands around its neck. Before it got loose, I grabbed the gas mask stuck on its face and pulled as it emitted a horrible screech of pain and anger. I finally got to my knife and stuck it in its neck.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_54">
		<text>As the dark shape approached him, Taras strained with all his being to match the mental power that was exerting itself upon him. He had been preparing for this moment, the trial in which he would defeat the genetic monstrosity at its own game - but now he was losing. Disjointed nightmare images flashed into his head as his awareness faltered. His last thought: "I failed."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_55">
		<text>He rifled through the pockets of the backpack: loose ammo, a Gieger counter, some hand-written notes now blurred by the blood... a fancy scientific container, probably with some artefact in it. "Thanks for the tip, buddy!", the looter said, gloating over the dead man. Little did he know that the team hunting that prize was now after him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_56">
		<text>After a long time waiting, I took my hand from the grenade and placed it beside me. The battle was over and they obviously weren't going to find me. The blast blew me into this little room and cracked my head against the wall. Now... I felt strange. I felt my cloudy surety fade and a disturbing idea take its place. Why was I trying to kill those people? Has the Monolith left me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_57">
		<text>I paced outside the door, wracked with indecision. It was a close shave and I was lucky to be alive. I should be running for the hills, but... Bursts of automatic fire and reverberating roars sounded in the warehouse. "Dammit, he's going to owe me." I put in a fresh mag and charged back in.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_58">
		<text>My head rapidly swivelled about. "You sure about that, Arytom? You're not kidding me?" As if on cue, Jager materialised in the doorway. "No, he's not kidding. I've gone on recon, and I've also spotted elements of Freedom stalkers en route through Pripyat. I questioned one, and he claims that someone has shut down the Brain Scorcher." Jager also appeared more alive than ever before. The notion that the Brain Scorcher, bane of all stalkers, could be shut down after all these months, was almost too good to be true.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_59">
		<text>Ozersky stared at the numbers on the screen until they were burning into his retina. It was a moment of profound despair for him. "We can't even describe what it is that we don't understand". If the Zone had previously thrown off all attempts at categorization, this test proved that they couldn't even rule anything out. Ozersky got over it - they would try again.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_60">
		<text>The only thing that was apparent to Pavlik was that his head really, really hurt, as well as a vague notion that he had to remember something important. He sat, with others like him, around a cold firepit in the pouring rain, and none of them knew why. Fleeting images of his past life sometimes appeared in Pavlik's head, but he didn't understand them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_61">
		<text>It was difficult living a double life, and Owl was now trying to cope with some sort of triple life. He still sent tips to his old friends in Yanov and even Dark Valley, but he had to keep that awfully quiet these days. He didn't mind his public persona - he had developed real camaraderie with some of Beard’s stalkers. Then there was his very secret life: sending cryptic data to the SSU.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_62">
		<text>I looked down at the body and it was obvious he wasn't going to make it. He had lost too much blood and, even without that, the infection was obvious down through the whole leg. The terrible thing was that I would have procured his death even if he had a chance; I hated myself for it, but it had been too long since my last taste and my hands were shaking.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_63">
		<text>With the dawn, I looked out over the fen and saw him, just a little black spot in the distance. It looks like I had neither closed the distance nor lengthened it; at least the anomalies prevented him from moving at night. I shouldered my bag and started at a brisk pace; no matter how far he went, I would catch him, and I would take back what is mine.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_64">
		<text>As the captain took the guitar in his hands, the rest of the group around the fire went silent - everyone already had great respect for the captain, but they had a sort of veneration for his music. After a moment of thought, the captain strummed beautiful, simple notes and took up a strange song in a low voice full of sorrow. They didn't even notice dawn approach.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_65">
		<text>Novikov took the rifle in hand and gave his visitor a look full of good-natured exasperation. "How did you even manage to twist the gas piston?" The other shrugged and said something about Chemic's home-made high-velocity ammunition. Novikov gave him a little chuckle and sent him out the door. "Ahh, yes. Here we have the finest minds the Zone has to offer..."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_66">
		<text>It had been a half-hour since they had seen the strange animal and the tourists were still excitedly discussing it. Suddenly, soldiers appeared in front of the bus and it screeched to a halt. Dozens of guns were trained on the windows and orders were shouted, but most passengers knew no Russian or Ukrainian. As they filed out, the Colonel radioed, "They've seen too much..."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_67">
		<text>The father and his son were attempting to make their way to the top of the hill, but the driving wind threatened to carry them away. They finally attained the summit and, over the flapping of their coats, the boy shouted, "Papa, what is that?" No need to point, they were both staring at the cyclone of circling winds over the far-off power plant. The father had no answer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_68">
		<text>This had gone on for nearly an hour and my nerves were at a breaking point. I stood in the middle of the bedroom and listened, straining to hear any movement in the dark house. I knew something was down there, and I had a nasty feeling it knew I was here as well. Why didn't it come up the stairs? I couldn't take it anymore. Breaking the silence, I kicked open the balcony door and jumped.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_69">
		<text>Sakharov's frosty impatience overfilled, and he cut the stalker short, "Young man, I do not know what you take me for, but I am not some senile geriatric, too gullible to know when he's being lied to. Either pay the agreed price or leave my facility." Black moved up behind the stalker and leered threateningly. "Good!”, Sakharov thought, "So that's what I'm paying him for!"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_70">
		<text>The scientist and his four protectors were standing in the middle of the circle of bonfires, each pointing a weapon out into the inky blackness. The last time they came those things had carried away the other scientist, and the group could feel their presence just outside the ring of light. Each of them was hoping against hope for the rise of the sun, but they all knew it was hours away.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_71">
		<text>I never thought I would wake up again, but that didn't make crawling out of a pile of corpses any more enjoyable. I desperately tried to remember what happened and where I might be now, but it was all jumbled up. However, I did know who brought me here, so I pulled a Beretta off of a corpse and checked the magazine. With fear in my heart, I left the concrete chamber.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_72">
		<text>The two heavily armed men left the passageway. As I peered out from my hiding place, I tried to figure out the quickest way outside before they came back. I picked a door and cautiously pushed it open, the pistol in my other hand. I had planned to use it on myself, to not let them get me... but I was unsure. I turned the corner into the face of a Monolith soldier.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_73">
		<text>Although I had planned to use it on myself, my instincts decided for me - I pointed the pistol at the fanatic and fired away. In a moment, I was running through the subterranean halls, looking for escape. I raced up a long flight of stairs and pushed open the steel door. Ahead, something like moonlight was shining through a window. Have I made it? I ran.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_74">
		<text>The fresh night air had never tasted so sweet, but I had little time to savor it. By now, they would know that someone had escaped, and they would all be searching with one mind. For the first time I observed my surroundings and realized I was in the middle of Pripyat. Chances seemed slim, but I ran for the nearest building, hiding in the dark from the white glow of the moon.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_75">
		<text>After the air-lock door had sealed, Professor Hermann hissed through his teeth. The interview had been frightening, not to mention humiliating. How could things get to this point? He thought of his prestige and the respect that he commanded in the outside world, the awards his research has garnered. Now he was being bullied by some gun wielding thug for protection money. He spat.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_76">
		<text>"Alright, so we can count you in tomorrow? We're going up to the old office building to look for artifacts." I told them yes. Later, I recited, "Five men, lightly armed and not expecting any fighting. They're going for artifacts." Stribog clasped my shoulder. "You have done well, my son. We need this." We tried to take as many alive as we could.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_77">
		<text>It was crippled, but it was still alive. It looked up at me with the fire of hate in its eyes and roared. Even in this situation, I was petrified. I fumbled with my shotgun and put it down for good, blowing its head clean open. Gonta walked up to my side and nodded in approval. "Well done - your first. That's one less bloodsucker to haunt the swamps."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_78">
		<text>"Just fucking go!" Stunned by the display of levitating objects in the first room, Rhino's words brought us to our senses. "Check your corners, keep moving!" We navigated the rooms in a near-panic, feeling the awful presence of something close; no amount of pay justified this. As we rushed through another lab a growl came from a dark corner. "Kill it, quick!" We emptied our mags into it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_79">
		<text>Smoke was flowing from the barrel of Zvyagintsev's rifle, but he kept up the volume of fire. Duty didn't have any squads to send, but the Major had volunteered to go alone. Mag after mag went into the Kalashnikov; it was so hot that rounds would occasionally cook off by themselves. By the time the barrel was warped, his foes were in retreat, supposing they had run into a heavy-weapons squad.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_80">
		<text>The archpriest frowned his well-worn face - he only heard distant things about the dangers of this area, but they were alarming enough. The young priest with the bright eyes had heard them too, but that only fired his enthusiasm. "Are we not meant to go where we are needed? There are men there who need the sacraments." The archpriest sighed - he knew he was right. "Go with God."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_81">
		<text>The gathering would have turned into a lynch-mob if there was more courage to go around. After much hesitation, a bold and experienced man stepped forward and spoke for the crowd, "We want you out of here, now. Otherwise we will make you leave." The blank-faced man thought for a moment; maybe it was time to ply his trade elsewhere. As he rose to his feet, the crown of men seemed to shrink back.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_82">
		<text>My search was over. I sunk down to the body, speechless. After they had shot him, they had stripped him, and they dumped out the things they didn’t want to loot from his bag. Then they had left him here, like waste - trash on the side of the road. I wanted to shout, to curse them, but I just couldn't. I took refuge in the silence before I had to make my report.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_83">
		<text>"So what's wrong with him?" "He thinks he's dead. That's all he talks about. We can't find anything seriously wrong with him; it's most likely emotional trauma." "Is this the guy we found in the mutant lair?" "Yeah. He had lain there all night, at least, with those freaks gathered around him. No idea why they left him alive, maybe they thought he was dead, too."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_84">
		<text>Four meters forward to pass the first anomaly on the right, then a right sharp turn and then you have to crawl. I had been following Pilot's instructions, but I was really nervous - I could never tell how far was too far. That's how I made my mistake. One extra step and I hear a whirring in my ear. Very much against my will, I get lifted up into the air.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_85">
		<text>"Sometimes," Jack said, closing his eyes, "it feels like you're being dishonest with me." Another pistol-whip added a red mark to the unfortunate man's face. "I think you need to do something to change that... or you'll find it hard to talk to anyone at all." They threw the man outside, there to lay for hours.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_86">
		<text>So the jerk comes walking in, all smiles and swagger, right up to me and starts telling me about his lucky find. And I smile back - just friendly old Beard. Then Grouse comes up behind and I change my tone. "You fell for it, shitbag. We planted that artefact to find out who's been stealing. And now here we are. So, you've got till dusk to leave Zaton, or we're going to ruin your day."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_87">
		<text>The Freedomers' hospitality was rather thin and hollow, and it showed everywhere. Gone were the days when a Freedomer would, without warning, come up to you and offer a joint of Cannabis and a large swig of vodka, and you would politely pocket the boof, but immediately accept the alcohol with unholy thirst. Those Freedomers were gone, and the ones we saw all held themselves in a joint atmosphere of utter bleakness and seriousness, and the weed and vodka had rotted away, leaving only curt greetings.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_88">
		<text>Max shot me a wink when he handed me the letter. "Here you go, you soft bastard." My heart started beating, as it always does during this time; it's a miracle that it even found me. I opened the letter and read the cherished and familiar handwriting. Then I just sat there for a while, the paper pushed against my face. It even smelled like home.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_89">
		<text>The indicators were letting off a deep and ominous alarm which made it really difficult to concentrate. We were going down and we didn't even know if we had been hit, but we had to find a place to land the massive MI-6. As we put down in the grassy clearing of a forest, I heard my co-pilot say, "I think we just landed in the God-damn Exclusion Zone."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_90">
		<text>For a moment, nothing happened. Then the sound of an explosion ripped through the air and the raiders sprang up, advancing quickly with weapons pointed at the APC. The vehicle was immobilized and smoke swirled up in the evening sky. A hatch opened and one of the crew fell limply to the ground. His dimmed eyes could only see the boots of a half-dozen men standing over him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_91">
		<text>I had managed to light a little fire. Some sort of electrical anomaly must have fried my torch... I didn't care to know any more. The flickering illumination reached to the walls where ancient signs seemed to me like the voices of the dead. It was my third day underground. There was no way out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_92">
		<text>My entire body was rigid as I sat staring into the inky darkness. One hand was on my pistol and the other held a flashlight and both were drenched in sweat. I had thought the room was safe. It was only after something had touched my foot in the darkness that I woke up. So here I was - listening to the thing moving around the room, not daring to turn on a light.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_93">
		<text>Sepp was in great form that night; he told the one about the German stalker's girlfriend which, I gather from the volume of laughter, they hadn't heard before. We broke out the beer we had been saving and everyone contributed something for a feast, a feast in the heart of the Zone! That was a good time. Where are they all now, I wonder?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_94">
		<text>Yar would fall into fits of melancholy sometimes, but he shut it away as not to bother his fellow Freedomers. Sometimes an image from his long life would plant itself in his mind and he could think of nothing else: a face in pain, a quiet sunrise, headlights flying over a dirt road. His friends didn't need to know - he had to keep it together.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_95">
		<text>"Major, our new friend is here." Major Czerny stood up as the visitor entered the command room. He got a good look at him: behind the slouching demeanor and dirty uniform, he saw the ease of a veteran soldier. The Major offered him a cigarette, which he took warily. The Major was in no hurry - Dushman's men were some of their best recruits.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_96">
		<text>The first report came from Pripyat, but most people dismissed it as a rumor. Two days later, the "rumor" wiped out an outpost north of Jupiter. Within a week it had been spotted in Dark Valley and then the Great Swamps. A Chimera alright, but it was covered with long, dark hair and roared like rending iron. Everyone was nervous - the Mercs even stopped going out at night.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_97">
		<text>It was the most terrible feeling that I have ever felt. I sat there, in the middle of the Bar, with laughter and drinking all around me, and I couldn't stop thinking about Denis. I left him. I left him to those fucking fanatics. What were they doing to him right now? Was he even alive? I wished I could drink it away, but I was sick all the way through.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_98">
		<text>If the stalker were to approach this one, he would be able to make out the bloodshot eyes and hear the incoherent mumbling of meaningless snatches from the man's former existence. He would also find out whether the old-model M16 in the zombie's hand still functioned, a risk he neither needed nor wanted to take. There was only one thing to do, an act both practical and decent. Dropping to one knee, the loner slipped the Mosin's sling off his shoulder, pulled the round knob of the rifle's cocking piece back and twisted it into the firing position.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_99">
		<text>The search team arrived in the clearing where the screams had been heard - it was a horrible mess. The dogs had gotten to him, and there were great smears of blood where the body had been dragged back and forth. They knew the victim was one of their own, but they had to get real close just to make the ID. That's when they heard the faint breathing and radioed back to Cold.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_100">
		<text>"What are those asswipes thinking? Is it funny? Hey, I'm talking to you, shithead!" Vector turned from his angry pacing back to the two carriers from Dead City, starting his rant anew. "What are those morons... I couldn't go take a shit with this amount of ammo! Hey, Kolin! Looks like we'll be using our shooters as clubs now!"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_101">
		<text>Silence fell in the camp as everyone turned and saw the lone figure walking slowly between the tents and the campfires, not seeming to take notice of anything. Some men slowly reached for their weapons, but most just stared in amazement. He passed through and out again into the evening mist. By all accounts, it was Dana Viking - killed by bandits a month ago.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_102">
		<text>He crouched down to pry a fist-sized stone from the soil beside his boot. "Let's play... catch the grenade!" It was a brilliant feint: a startled yelp could be heard as the 'grenade' landed and convinced the merc to run away from the assumed center of blast – leaving him wide open to the loner marksman. The Mosin's seventy year old stock thumped reassuringly against its wielder's shoulder, a hundred and forty-eight grains of copper-jacketed Soviet power blasting through the unfortunate merc's kevlar vest like a fist through a wet paper bag.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_103">
		<text>Just as I looked up the long, grassy slope, the morning sun swept over the landscape into the forest glen. My feet were sore and my pack was heavy, but I felt happier than I've felt in a long time. Maybe I'd just drop the package and turn east until I walked myself right out of the Zone. All your money and artefacts can't buy this kind of peace.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_104">
		<text>Emerging from the underpass, the loner saw a figure staggering in circles just down the road. It was a zombified stalker, an unfortunate soul who'd no doubt wandered here from Yantar after suffering terrible brain damage in the powerful fields of psionic energy which hung over the deserted complex overlooking the dried-up lake. They all ended up the same: mindless husks in dirty uniforms, shambling aimlessly until they died of exposure somewhere.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_105">
		<text>I had my hand on the rusty old door handle when Vinogradov stopped me. "No, no, no. Like this." He banged his fist on the steel of the door and immediately we heard a chorus of hoarse groans from within. "See?", he said, unpinning a grenade, "You should always knock first."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_106">
		<text>We crossed the fence into the Iron Forest, and immediately a bullet hit the concrete right next to my foot. Vadim raised his rifle and ducked back behind the steel fence. In the low light, every shadow was alien and any darkened silhouette could have been another person. Just then, I was knocked back as a round impacted on my Nosorog’s shoulder armor. Thankfully, my attacker wasn’t using a silencer, so his muzzle flash gave him away. I zeroed in and raised my assault rifle to my face, peering down the scope...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_107">
		<text>Most people who met Pavlik the Gun didn't forget him - loud, overconfident and overbearing. He was obsessed with his shooter - stuck a bunch of fancy electronics on it and spent his time loading his own match ammunition. Wouldn't shut up about it. Naturally, he stepped into an electro one day and that was the end of him. Never even took a shot outside of target practice.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_108">
		<text>"Nikolai, you bastard! That grenade lob was far too close to us, you could have hit us!" With an insulted look, Nikolai holstered his M79 and retorted, "Hey, you don't know how hard it was to place that shot!. Besides, look at you, fisting a poor Bloodsucker to death. Are you sure you don't have a fetish?" "Shut the fuck up, Nikolai." I tried to respond, even as I joined the rest of the squad in laughter. The tension and stress that had plagued us for days had been broken, and with newfound morale we continued our sojourn towards Limansk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_109">
		<text>Konstantin was desperately trying to guess how many rounds he had left in the magazine, but he didn't dare take his aim from the doorway. Suddenly, two of his squad-mates ran past him and down the hallway. Before he could decide what to do, an invisible hand seemed to grab onto his rifle and nearly wrenched it out of his hand.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_110">
		<text>Two soldiers from the border detail sat on some old crates and smoked away. They had a good laugh over the new joke making the rounds: "Shoot any suspicious particles on sight!" Neither of them had a clue why so much security was needed in such a place - obviously, they were being kept in the dark about something. Not to mention all these sinister types in civilian clothing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_111">
		<text>"Look at him, comrade. Look into the eyes beneath his Altyn. Do you see any joy? Or hope? No. All that is in his expression is pain. A man afraid to die. A man full of regret and fear. He was like you once. Young, and eager to fight. Now look at him... This is all you have to look forward to..."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_112">
		<text>That day was when Krylov almost got what was coming to him. We just entered the lab when he started behaving erratically. When he tried putting his gun into his mouth, I figured that he had lied to me about buying the psy-protection. You can't teach some people. So I held him down and didn't stop beating his face until he gave up struggling. He could thank me later.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_113">
		<text>Pachowitz was the resident expert on radiation dispersal. He sat in a little cubicle in the UNISG forward headquarters, located around thirty kilometers from the edge of the Zone, and spent most of his time reviewing sensor data and campaigning Field Command to get him more. For him, the Zone was a collection of charts and meteorology reports.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_114">
		<text>It was dark and quiet around camp and the first snow of the year was falling. Ignatich made his rounds and stopped to chat with Spore, one of the few still awake. Back outside, he looked up at the white, heavy flakes falling out of the black sky. He coughed as he smoked his cigarette - he was new to smoking. As he looked over to his right, he saw two glowing eyes on the roof of the HQ.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_115">
		<text>They brought in one of our new guys, really just a kid, in on a stretcher. Acute radiation sickness - just riddled with it. He was red like a beet and after he wasn't able to vomit anymore, he just retched with his whole body. I got him on the saline and looked down on this kid, utterly miserable and probably a goner, and I realized that he looked just like my cousin. Exactly like him. It's a waste.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_116">
		<text>A cloud of fear and desperation hung over the man. He showed up in loner settlements to stay the night, and they would find him gone before the sun had risen. He walked with an urgent pace everywhere he went, and an exhausted, dismal look hung in his eyes. He could never feel safe; he knew they were hunting him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_117">
		<text>Before turning in for the night, Bruno jammed up the door and checked his tripwire. Kneeling down over his sleeping bag, Bruno thought back over the events of the day: all of the long miles he had traveled, the people he had seen... and his close brush with death. Bruno had a good aim and a fighting spirit, and he was grateful for it. He softly intoned the well-known words: "Our Father..."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_118">
		<text>"Then don’t take the job, I don’t give a shit! I have ten other groups who would be more than willing to take the job, so either gear up or get lost!" Dushman said this to the reluctant merc who began inspecting his rifle. Once the merc was done, he stood up, looked Dushman straight in the eye, and left without a word.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_119">
		<text>"This", the buyer pointed at the Meat Chunk artefact, "is clearly not what you called me for. Let's get to real business." Shrugging his shoulders, Ragged took the thing off the table and picked a container out of his bag. "As you like, but you'll have to be pretty persuasive for... well, ever heard of a Full Empty?" The buyer leaned forward with interest.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_120">
		<text>Vasiliev had just demolished the Q Zone theory and was really heating up. I asked him what he thought of Tellemann's theory. "Inane!", he shouted as we grinned like schoolboys. "Listen, children: Telleman's got his metaphysical axe to grind, and he's convinced that his psuedo-scientific despair is gloriously incarnate in the Zone. Until he presents a cogent argument, he can go to Hell!"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_121">
		<text>I brandished my knife in front of me while the pack of freaks closed in on all sides. Some were screeching and bellowing - taunting their beaten prey. One tentatively stepped closer and I lunged, screaming and swinging. It pulled back with a sullen look as I whipped around, trying to watch all sides. That's when I heard the crack of bullets and the beasts began to fall.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_122">
		<text>I had rigged a sort of makeshift sling for my broken arm, but it didn't stop the pain from shooting all the way up into my spinal cord. I dragged my feet through the doorway and peered around into the dark room - totally empty. I didn't have the strength to do anything more than let my shotgun clatter to the ground and sink into the corner. Sleep instantly overcame me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_123">
		<text>Muzzle flashes erupted in the early morning mist as the Duty patrol sighted the Freedom outpost. Both sides moved to cover and the fight was destined to be a protracted one. Confusion reigned as another firefight intersected into this one: a loner hunting party fleeing from a mercenary fireteam. The sun continued to rise as the casualties mounted.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_124">
		<text>I took the empty flask from my lips and threw it aside. I looked ahead into the pulsating orbit of humming and hissing anomalies, but my mind was elsewhere. Here I was - doing the only thing I was good at. Honestly, I'd rather it was something less exciting. Damn the alcohol and damn those crooks who sell it to me. I sniffed the air; seemed like a good chance for a Night Star.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_125">
		<text>Dust fell from the rattling rafters as the surge mounted horribly outside. A handful of frightened men huddled up beneath the tin roof and waited helplessly; this was not a tested structure and none of them knew what sort of protection it would offer. Each wave, in blinding orange and purple, seemed to shake the entire building like a ship in a storm.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_126">
		<text>He watched carefully, eagerly, from his hiding place, his hungry eyes following every move of the unsuspecting stranger. Suddenly, the same old mistake was made and the stranger was history - his equipment slung everywhere by the force of the anomaly. The scavenger crawled from his hiding place, jealously snatching up the dead man's gear before retreating back into his hole.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_127">
		<text>It was nearly dusk when Nimble found himself in the remote little grove where his outside contact had hidden the shipment. The wary stalker had spent the entire day winding this way and that, throwing off potential trackers with false trails and distractions. Some might think this procedure excessive. Nimble didn't. He'd seen enough to know how rarely the Zone forgives mistakes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_128">
		<text>I couldn't tell you if it was a dream or not. I was sitting before a calm lake under the brightening grey of a dawn sky and I saw movement out in the middle of the water. I looked and saw the form of a man rise up out of the depths and hold out his hand to me. He said something to me that I understood, but no longer remember. Imperceptibly, he slipped back under the water.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_129">
		<text>Ghost picked up his Groza and checked the scope and suppressor. "I don't know if I can cover you all the way," he warned, turning the compact rifle over and removing the magazine. "This ammo is cheap shit." "You could use mine," Tiger offered. "It shoots a little high inside three hundred meters, but it groups all right." "That's very kind of you." "I'm being practical." Tiger eased the Mosin's leather sling off his shoulder and handed the rifle to Ghost. "It's in my best interest to see this through."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_130">
		<text>"When did you get this armband?" The exo merc asked. The squad leader slowly drew out the armband and gave it to him, responding "September 2011." The exo merc slowly inspected the entire armband, then suddenly ripped open a secret compartment in the armband, drawing out a concealed piece of paper. With a quick glance at the paper, he handed the armband back to the leader. "This is a form of communication that we discontinued years ago. Barely anyone remember this type of message."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_131">
		<text>"Right here", said Sparrow, pushing his finger on the old satellite map, leaving a tobacco smudge. It was night and we were huddled around a makeshift table in the train hanger. I looked at him doubtfully. "There? In the middle of Red Forest?" He nodded, enjoying his role. He knew I was in anyway - it was too good to pass up.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_132">
		<text>Was Strelok also dead? Ghost had no evidence to the contrary, and despite his own wishes he had come to accept that it was now up to him to take over the task of returning to the center of the Zone. After he'd finished this mission and helped the scientists deal with the Yantar psi-generator, he'd head for the Cordon and find Guide. Guide should know where Doc had secreted himself, and Doc might know what had become of Strelok. It was a forlorn hope, but it was all he had left.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_133">
		<text>Beep-beep! Beep-beep! Semenov froze. How could he have forgotten to turn off the detector's audio output!? Now all the zombies were gathering around him, bleary eyes watching intently. "Uh..." Thinking fast, he began to push buttons semi-randomly with the same stabbing motion as before. "Hurr, durr..." By some miracle, it worked. "Science," the zombie merc proclaimed astutely. Within a few seconds, Semenov's audience had reached the conclusion that their new friend was indeed a scientific zombie.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_134">
		<text>The ruined village was as he remembered it: a cluster of structures still mostly intact – apart from the one which an anomaly had taken a large bite out of – bordered by a fringe of crumbling foundations and bare chimneys already claimed by the creeping waters of the swamp. On the north side, a few stalwart trees offered shade. A dirt road led east to the machine yard, while a winding series of footpaths and wooden walkways offered access to the boat park a short distance northwest.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_135">
		<text>I only left him for five minutes at the most. He wanted me to check in on something that Xenotech owed him, and when I came back he was gone. No trace - nothing. We sent out a search party in the dark, but we couldn't get far. The next day we looked everywhere. Grisha Lark had simply disappeared into thin air.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_136">
		<text>The situation was very tense, and Hatchet knew that the only thing keeping things together was discipline. They had no objective, their contacts had disappeared, and they were left out in unfriendly country to figure it out. The monsters howled outside the walls and the occasional skirmish with unknown hostiles broke the monotony. Hatchet was starting to feel like a small fish in a big pond.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_137">
		<text>The mist was slowly dying under the growing strength of the morning sun as the group of men silently made their way through the field. The wild grass was very high, nearly up to the chest, and they were crowned with dew. The man in front stops every once and a while and warily throws a bolt - but all is clear so far.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_138">
		<text>Some time ago, there was a man well known to most of the factions, though never by name, for he changed his name often. He was an opportunist, playing one side off against the other. Usually, when someone wanted him dead, he was far away cutting deals with someone else. He was always the master of the situation and the pieces.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_139">
		<text>Osip knew nothing about stalkers. He'd never heard the term. But he was one, in his own manner. After the death of his parents, he resolved to hold the family property for the rest of his life, and he did so alone. Even after things got strange and nature became corrupted and dangerous.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_140">
		<text>Facial recognition helps foster human sympathy. Masks and sleep deprivation both have a negative impact on facial recognition, and therefore make it easier to dehumanize your victims.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_141">
		<text>The previous attempts to secure a crossing in the Jupiter Underground had failed - scattered and cut-off by whatever was living down there. The Captain, leader of the new attempt, took no chances. When the doors opened up, they formed a firing line and doused the tunnel with lead; several light machine guns with plenty of ammo were brought for this purpose. The opposition was drowned in gunfire.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_142">
		<text>The days blurred into one long sequence of careful hikes through the wilderness and uneasy sleep. Igor had always shunned others, and he determined to get to the North his own way. In time, his mind began to lose clarity and he performed his daily activity mechanically. At some point the incremental psy-waves left him brain-dead.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_143">
		<text>It was a long time until he stopped screaming, but the hoarse whispering was almost worse. He wanted me to kill him right there, to stop the agony. But I hadn't given up on him yet. I continued to drag him down the long, dusty road. The noontime sun shone on his legs - no more than scorched stumps.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_144">
		<text>The mercenary had heard stories about this anomaly - he had even seen videos. But nothing could prepare him for the reality - for the feeling of being pulled towards the center, for the feeling and sound of his own flesh being torn apart by invisible force-fields. He felt the warmth of his own blood, and cried out in agony as he was slowly stripped down to his very soul.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_145">
		<text>Killing your fellow man is universally considered to be a detestable and heinous action. But this is the Zone, so why should you care?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_146">
		<text>We were all sitting around the fire when Leshiy came back. Walking by, he interrupted his stride for a moment to just shake his head before continuing on. He was really gone then - if Leshiy can't find him, no-one can. We looked at his guitar, still sitting in its place by the fire. We would have played something, but the best musician was gone forever.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_147">
		<text>“That being said, I know this might sound fucking nuts, but if I was in your shoes, I’d take matters into my own hands and go see Aslan.” My colleague blew out a puff of smoke. “Not to turn yourself in, obviously. Go at night, sneak into the Merc base and steal Aslan’s PDA; that way, you could find out who put out the contract.” “Oh sure,” Mikhail barked a laugh. “Break into a compound stuffed to the gills with corrupt, murderous, heavily-armed assholes who'd shoot their own fucking mothers for a ruble and a pack of cigs? Tell me you’re not serious.”</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_148">
		<text>They hadn't beaten him, they hadn't even said a word to him. The spy was taken into some basement and thrown down on the ground. A ring of a dozen men stood around, but one directly in front of him stepped forward. "What you attempted to achieve by deception, you will achieve now in truth. Welcome, brother." After more silence, Charon signaled to his men.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_149">
		<text>He thought that he could re-enter the world when he left the Zone. What he found was a brooding sense of apprehension over his entire life. Some fear deep inside him whispered that he had never really left.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_150">
		<text>All was tranquil within the ruined room as The Marked One entered. The voice that had been calling seemed to now overwhelm him. "Come to me. I am what you have been seeking. You have wisdom: you know that man's desires are never fulfilled. I am that fulfillment. You will have anything. You will have everything. Come to me to take that which you desire."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_151">
		<text>When I thought it was safe, I climbed up onto a little hill and looked back upon the Zone. I had left. Funnily enough, I left in one piece and not much richer or poorer than when I had entered. A dark cloud passed over the sky and veiled the forests and marshes from sight. It was over. I turned again towards my new life.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_152">
		<text>I started running back to the Courier's location. Once I got within a relatively close distance to him I looked back up from the PDA. That was when I saw something in front of me, In the moment I thought it was just some random mutant. I was so fucking wrong.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_153">
		<text>The two remaining men started to run, seeing no chance to kill the creature. Dropping a PDA beacon entitled "VERY DANGEROUS AREA - STAY AWAY," they quickly left the area, as the giant started to drag the two bodies back into the factory.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_154">
		<text>Nobody in my squad nor platoon volunteered to be in the Zone, as we had all been conscripted, but we tried to have fun. For a while we treated it like it was a camping trip adventure, where we would sing songs around the campfires at night sharing vodka and playing the guitar. We forgot about death for around a month, before we had our first casualty. When we arrived they were in pieces. We carried them back to base in body bags. No one dared to look them in the eye.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_155">
		<text>Nothing. Quiet as a grave. The leader nodded and opened the door. As soon as they shined their lights into the room they were met by a hailstorm of cinder blocks, teapots and other household junk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_156">
		<text>To my right, which was to the North, there stood, very far away, the House of Silence, upon a low hill. And in that house were many lights, and no sound. And so it had been through an uncountable eternity of years. Always those steady lights, and not a single whisper of sound. The danger of this house had accounted for the greatest danger of all these lands.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_157">
		<text>Asking people to join your squad makes their deaths your responsibility. Good thing you're worth more to your faction then they are.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_158">
		<text>Cognitive dissonance is an uncomfortable feeling caused by holding two conflicting ideas simultaneously.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_159">
		<text>Nothing is the same as it was before. You can feel more despair from the people around you and sometimes you find pockets of nature within these concrete jungles that were not there before. Sometimes it feels like we never truly survived, that we lost a part of ourselves during all the chaos. Is this what it's like to survive? To survive where others have died? A question I hope never has an answer. Now I lay against the grass and peer up to the foggy clouds, hoping to find myself from all that has happened.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_160">
		<text>I listened to their stories and songs, while keeping an ear out for danger. In the midst of the laughter, a question was raised: “What brought you to the Zone?” There was a brief moment of silence, before someone spoke. “Why, for the adventure,” a Loner said with a grin. “Money,” a Mercenary answered. “To protect the world from the Zone,” a Dutyer followed. “To learn the truth,” an Ecologist replied. I nodded as I listened to each answer, then found their expectant gazes upon me. “And what of you?” the Stalker asked. I pondered the question. "To find myself."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_161">
		<text>Families rarely learn about what happens to their relatives who enter the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_162">
		<text>There it was with an ominous glow and strange aura, as the detector was beeping continuously signaling to us that we had finally uncovered an artifact. I said to my friends, "we are going to be rich!" Just then, I heard movement coming from the thick foliage behind us. "Hands in the air bitches! No sudden movements!" It was a squad of 6 bandits, dressed in black overcoats and armed with fully automatic AK rifles, pointed directly at us. "Put the artefact on the ground and no one gets hurt!"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_163">
		<text>A lone Stalker stared up at the dark sky. He could have been sitting like this for days, or maybe even years. He couldn't tell any more. Time had lost its meaning long ago - it was no longer measured in minutes, nor years, but in lives.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_164">
		<text>Walking through the streets of Pripyat. No Monolith, no mutants, nothing. Just the quiet rustle of the trees as he held his AKM that's gotten him so far. His Geiger counter begins to crackle lightly as he approaches the ferris wheel... but that doesn't matter. He has his SEVA suit that's helped him travel so deep into the Zone... certainly only a few stalkers have seen this. His entire life as a stalker portrays itself in his mind as he pushes deeper into the Sarcophagus in search of the Wish Granter. He ponders his wish for a moment. What is your wish, stalker?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_165">
		<text>"Don't!-" That was all I had time to say before the rookie I was with walked up to the Monolith soldier laying on the floor. Within an instant there was a loud boom and the stalker standing in front of me was nothing more than a fine red mist covering the room. I was launched out of the building and onto a car parked down on the road. My back hurt like hell, but at least I was still alive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_166">
		<text>It was quite dark now and a fine rain was dripping onto the asphalt, like tiny needles. I waited outside in the shadow of the apartment building, waiting for the door to open. On the third ring, it finally opened and a middle-aged man with a goatee came out lighting a cigarette and looking around nervously. I nodded my head in a non-threatening manner. "The Package is secure."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_167">
		<text>The Duty soldiers were firing nonstop. It was to the point that smoke had gotten so thick they could no longer see, and the distinct smell of gunpowder was far and wide throughout Rostok. Something was wrong; a pack of wild dogs is one thing, but these things were something else entirely.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_168">
		<text>The stalker slowly took off his mask. The sound of the Geiger Counter had faded and in his final moments he felt a strange sense of calm and peace. Clutching a photo of his family he whispered, "I can’t wait to see you again."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_169">
		<text>"I'm not saying shit!" The Stalker, bloodied and bruised with his hands and feet bound together, was tossed down a flight of stairs. "Don’t worry, we will keep you alive, but just remember: Owl always gets people to talk sooner or later."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_170">
		<text>A Duty squad was advancing in formation through the forest. The sky was overcast with clouds, providing an eerie aura that made all but the most experienced stalkers uneasy. There had been a few attacks this week - it'd be dangerous out here. Suddenly, the pointman spotted a figure moving in the shadows ahead. He dropped to the ground, motioning for the rest of the squad to do the same, and started crawling. On the radio, he whispered, "This is Corporal Alexi. We've made contact with an unknown and potentially hostile element. How copy, over?"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_171">
		<text>Professor Herman looked at the glowing object with pure amazement. He had given up hope on it ever existing, but there it was staring at him. "Oasis is real? How is this even possible? Maybe this will get me that Nobel Prize and better funding for my project," He thought to himself while still in astonishment. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_172">
		<text>The mercenary waited around the corner with his PKM, listening for a sound of footsteps. He had been doing this for what felt like hours now. Suddenly, he heard it. A single footstep coming from the corridor behind. He quickly raised the barrel and let loose a volley of rounds, completely decimating the incoming loner. "Just another goddamn day in The Zone..." he muttered to himself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_173">
		<text>The old man shivered before the fire in his tattered coat. His hands were wrapped around a steaming bowl of cabbage stew, a rarity he hoped would calm his shaking nerves.  He watched the fire consume the scraps of the once-proud wood. “That bastard…” he started, “that bastard and his men. How they taunted me while I dug that grave...” He stared deeply into the flames.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_174">
		<text>A trio of bandits sat in front of their fire on a late autumn night. They were all fairly drunk, playing cards and making jokes at each others' expenses - normal evening fare for bandits. The oldest, Volodya, looked from one of his friends to the other and back again. "Look, guys. I have an idea..." "Not the knife throwing thing again. You missed my hand and killed the dog last time, you old fool!" grumbled Yegor. "No, not that, something better!" "Ok, spit it out then!" "Tonight, we rob Sultan!"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_175">
		<text>I sat in my tent, nursing my last shot of whiskey. There was nothing much to do anymore - the Renegades had been decimated by Clear Sky over the past couple months and it was a struggle to get any sort of supplies. We didn't really have a cause. The Zone had taken so much from me - my life, my health, my will. But I wouldn't give it the satisfaction of knowing it beat me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_176">
		<text>"I am starting to worry about you and your... problem." The stalker said to his drunk mate. "Yeah, I’ve got a problem! I am stuck here in the Zone, and I am all out of booze! Now make yourself useful and bring me some more beer!" He demanded, slurring every word. The stalker looked down at the ground, seemingly disappointed by the response. "Don't you see that you've become an addict?" The stalker pleaded. "What is it to you? It's not like I'm hurting anyone." The drunk smiled and replied, "No one except myself..." He had a point.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_177">
		<text>"If anyone ever says there is not a symphony to war, then they have never seen combat. The sound of machine guns firing becomes rhythmic, with boots stomping across the battlefield, knives tearing through armor and into flesh. It all begins to sound like music created by the Devil’s orchestra."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_178">
		<text>The stalker leaned down beside another who was sitting on the ground sobbing profusely. "It's okay man, you did what you had to do. It was your life or his." The consoling stalker took his mask off, reached into his bag and handed the crying stalker a piece of chocolate. "Don't let anyone fool you. We've all been in your shoes and anyone who says it was easy is a damn liar. You will never get over it, but it will get easier. I promise."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_179">
		<text>I walked into the Bar, hoping that maybe there was something new. The barkeep knew what I wanted - not that it ever took more words than that - as I downed the vodka, taking the burn as payment for my sins. My head sunk into my hands. Was there a bottom to this hole? I had my own fair share of blood on my hands - my own share of guilt. I couldn't even tell which one felt worse anymore. All I'd ever known was death. But after all that, after everything... I just wanted a drink.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_180">
		<text>We had been defending the barrier for hours. The machine guns were all overheated and the munitions were running low. They just kept coming and they didn't care if they lived or died. "Shit... I’m out of ammo... there's only one option left," the stalker was a bomb maker and when we saw him pull the pin on that grenade, we knew the end result. He went out in one hell of a blaze and the crater in the road is where those zombie cultists shot him down. He saved our lives that morning.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_181">
		<text>When the Colonel walked into the room, we could tell that something was not right. It was just the way he was acting, and you could cut the tension in the air with a knife. Nobody saw it coming when he pulled out his Makarov and shot our Staff Sergeant twice in the head. "Does anyone else feel like selling guns to stalkers now?"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_182">
		<text>"Get down and whatever you do, don't stop moving!" The sniper had us dialed in and was laying down suppressive fire, but Pavlov did not care. "These fools think I haven’t been shot at before, but I’ve been a soldier since I was 6!" Pavlov was not his real name, but nobody knew how to say his real name. Poor guy told me once he was a child soldier who used to live in a place called "The Congo." Apparently, he fled for the Zone and learned Russian while he was here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_183">
		<text>"Stop aiming for the head, aim for the base of the neck and you will connect more shots." Hunting people was never something I wanted training in. In fact, I used to be a pacifist, but during the occupation our people were being round up and slaughtered like cattle. Any perceived opposition was executed publicly. I miss home, but I can never go back. I still dream of leaving this place and helping others instead of taking their lives.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_184">
		<text>"You know those things will kill you right?" The stalker said, concerned. "Seriously? There are anomalies that can kill you almost instantly, radioactive air in lethal doses, mutants that can clean the flesh off a living person in seconds, and psy storms that can literally fry your brain... and *you're* worried about me having a *smoke?*"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_185">
		<text>I managed to take two down with my gun, before a third one bit my forearm and another pounced on my back, pushing me down to the ground. Taras was nowhere to be seen, and the rookie's sawn-off blasted next to my ear, turning one of the dogs into minced meat, covering me with blood and innards.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_186">
		<text>He felt the pain of the shot long before he heard the sound. He collapsed to the floor, clutching his shoulder. He knew it was bad, but not how bad. He heard his comrades yelling, but their voices sounded muffled. He knew he was bleeding out. "This is it," he thought, "I'll die never knowing what it feels like to be happy..." Then - a sharp ringing, as everything went black.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_187">
		<text>He was completely unaware. I laid there with my crosshairs aimed at the base of his neck like I was trained to. "Squeeze the trigger, just a quick squeeze and it's over. You've done this countless times before, what makes this any different?" I didn't know why, but I couldn't bear to watch. I closed my eyes and squeezed the trigger; I heard my PDA beep a few moments afterwards and knew the job was done.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_188">
		<text>The bandit's train of thought was quickly shattered as the sound of automatic gunfire and screams suddenly surrounded him. He quickly grabbed his TOZ and rushed outside to see a pack of lurkers terrorizing his "friends." Those beasts seemed somewhat otherworldly. Mutants seemed wrong already, but also felt like they belonged to the Zone. Lurkers... they seemed to be from another reality, one of ruin and eternal winter. Nonetheless, 12 gauge shells seemed to work on them as well as any other, and the beasts were defeated. "You two owe me."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_189">
		<text>The stalker was furious, he continued to shout, "you stupid fucking idiot! Why didn't you tell us you couldn't read a map when we gave it to you!? Why are you laughing, huh!? We are literally lost in the North and in case you didn't realize we are not exactly welcomed by the locals!" The hooded man did not answer, he merely kept chuckling to himself. All went silent when he took off his balaclava and revealed his face.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_190">
		<text>"That is over a 300 percent profit for your fat ass! What, you don't think we know about your prices? I don't know if you need that extra money to keep that bald head of yours waxed or what, but you can either change your prices or find a new dealer." Sidorovich, knowing he couldn't pass up the opportunity, reluctantly made a new offer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_191">
		<text>It was only then that he noticed that the knife was still in his shoulder. He had been so distracted by the pain that he had missed it. Even a year of experience had not prepared him for this amount of agony. He was in shock, but he still pulled the blade from his body. It was surprisingly hard to get it out, as it was stuck in the flesh. He dropped the bloodstained knife and collapsed onto his knees.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_192">
		<text>A splash drew my attention to the left. I slowed down and unclipped my rifle from my chest. Vadim cursed and aimed his rifle, tracking the Flesh as it ran past us. “Hold your fire!” I exclaimed on my helmet’s radio. Vadim whipped around. “Why? What’s going on?” “Flesh don’t run unless they're hunting, or something’s chasing them!” I shot back. “Keep your eyes on the bushes!” There was no sound other than the Flesh’s fading footsteps. I strained my ears, listening hard for anything out of place, until I heard it...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_193">
		<text>A drop from the IV bag entered into the patient's vein. His body tensed and his eyes rolled back into his skull. The medic cursed. "They are dying faster than we can treat them! Does anyone have any answers? What is happening to my men?" Viktor growled under his breath, the slightest bit of anxiety poking through. The medic could do nothing — only watch the life leave their bodies. Once upon a time, he would have cried. The senseless waste of life, the injustice of it. Now he simply stared at the floor and contemplated.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_194">
		<text>"I miss him every day. I still haven't gone artefact hunting since his death. It just hurts too much to think about how he would get so excited when we saw that dot on the detector. I buried him with our detector, his wife’s photo and his PKM. I carry his patch in my pocket to remind myself it can all end in an instant. God, I miss him. Why did you have to take him and not me? He was such a good stalker..."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_195">
		<text>We were pinned down at the pump station, Renegades all around and bullets flying everywhere. I had just watched the guy next to me get mowed down the second he raised his head to lay covering fire. That is when we heard it. Explosion after explosion followed by the sound of our once mortal enemy coming to our aid. Some soldiers from Duty heard our S.O.S. and came over to kick Renegade ass. Maybe those guys aren't so bad...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_196">
		<text>"When you hold this mystery of the Zone in your hands, you feel how your skin becomes tougher and less sensitive. You can still shoot through it with a bullet, but it's much more difficult to cut through," said the trader. Before me was the weirdest object I had ever seen in my entire life, somehow glowing and pulsating with unknown energy. Hell, the thing was even floating a few inches off the table. I wanted to learn as much as possible about these so called "artefacts."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_197">
		<text>As I sat with the campfire going and a couple bottles of Vodka, I was overcome by a sense of how insignificant I was in this world. "Just another stalker in the Zone...", I thought morosely. "Someone else will come by, sit down at this fire and will never even know I was here. They'll pass me by and I'll be but a breath in this world, gone and forgotten in a moment. Who will come after me and who came before?" I sighed and took another sip.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_198">
		<text>In a small building across the substation, a black-hooded head ducked down in a window. I took a breath and waited. A few seconds later, the man in the building peeked over the windowsill, and a round from my rifle blew the top of his head open, splattering the wall behind him like a fucked-up Pollock painting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_199">
		<text>The Geiger counter was clicking loudly and continuously. My comrade said, "can't you shut that thing up?" As we creeped through the dark space and corridors of the lab. The leader of the group said "shhh... Do you hear that?" In the distance the faint sound of a child's cry emerged. "Weapons hot, that's no child..."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_200">
		<text>I used to see him now and then in the research camp when I came back with loot to sell. He looked like a normal lad. Big and robust, you'd never think him one of the eggheads. He gave me a good price on artefacts, was always happy to chat about this and that... and what a stupid end. He was fussing with his gear near a Whirlgig when these rascals started to shoot. He got thrown into the anomaly, then twisted. When we finished fighting, there was nothing left but the shreds of his overalls mixed with bloody chunks of skin tissue.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_201">
		<text>Beneath the cover of a thousand twisted trees the gunmetal clouds congregated, spewing forth an endless torrent that drowned out the sounds of the dying forest with the clatter of rain against the arid ground. Soon the dirt became thick mud sloshing up to our knees, bringing our walking to a slog. We ran for the nearest tree, a hundred-year-old mess of black bark and crooked spines. The rain could still seep through but at least there was some shelter - for now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_202">
		<text>How long he's been paddling around this cold, glass lake, he doesn't know. Where he's from, his own name, all other meaningful pieces of his personal puzzle are a haze. A haze that parallels the reaching fog around him, trapping him, leading him further from its shores. The waves lapping the side of his small boat match the muddled waves of his own thought, angering him in his own deep waves of confusion. Onwards, he paddles, wondering just where the fog might take him...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_203">
		<text>Crossing the border into Yantar, I took another look at Lars Asimov. His gear was good, but obviously new; he couldn’t have been in the Zone for more than a couple weeks. My theory was quickly confirmed when a Tushkano scurried across our path, and Lars practically jumped out of his skin, tracking the small mutant with his SG552.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_204">
		<text>The merc stood, completely frozen and unable to move, staring in pure, unadulterated horror as the the abomination down the dark concrete hall crept ever closer, reaching its almost claw-like hand towards him. Piercing frequencies rang through his skull from within. Voices called out from both everywhere and nowhere at once, commanding him to surrender his very soul. The lone merc prayed to every god that he knew and even some that he didn't for a way out. Unfortunately for him, his mind went blank — there were none that could save him now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_205">
		<text>Ghost had been sincere in his promise not to betray the other neutral. He had no real choice about it: if he tried anything here, Sakharov would see to it that he was forever blacklisted from doing work for the ecologists or for Duty, and Barkeep or Sidorovich could easily put a price on his head to boot. Regardless of his obligations, the veteran felt ill at ease watching the back of his could-be rival. His dislike for Tiger straddled the division between professional and personal.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_206">
		<text>"So, this is how it ends..." Misha thought to himself. Everything had gone wrong, from the mission, to his team, and finally, this. Misha turned his head slowly. "You?" There was a brief silence when Misha realized he knew the man who stood behind him. It was almost enough to make him laugh — of all the people to be here, it was him. It was always him. "You were the one who..." In the blink of an eye, a bullet pierced his skull. There wasn't even enough time to register the pain that would have been felt had he been shot elsewhere. Only darkness remained.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_207">
		<text>Cold shifted through documentation in his office, checking logistics reports from Spore and Novikov, reading up on rumours gathered by Nimble up north and analyzing research rundowns made by various Clear Sky field commanders. He took a sip from the steel mug on his desk. Librarian's tea was his only respite ever since he had to quit alcohol. Kalancha had given him two options, go clean or die within a couple years. Even in less dire situations, when Kalancha gave health-related advice, it was better to live by it than suffer the consequences.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_208">
		<text>Boris had returned from his task at the river outpost, and the chimera he killed now partially occupied Cold's desk. "Next time, could you perhaps notify me of a chimera? You know, the biggest, baddest mutant in the Zone? Not pass it off as a cat?" Boris bellowed. "Nah, I was sure you'd handle it. How about that PDA?" Cold asked with a smirk. "Yeah, I accidentally slipped and dropped it in a bunch of grime from the chimera, oopsie daisies. Here you go," Boris said, handing Cold the filthiest PDA since somebody stole Yar's "me time" PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_209">
		<text>As his gun jammed he screamed "Hajde! Idi jebi se!" rushing to unjam the stubborn old AK. Croatian bastard, I have no idea what he said but probably something along the lines of, "gonna have me a nice boar stew tonight!" The pack of boars retreated into the wilderness as we chased them down, rifles in hand.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_210">
		<text>Now, I've got an offer for you. Y'see, the blue swamp-lovers absolutely despise you. They want you gone, but I'm willing to give you an option. Leave this place, and you get to keep your sorry asses," Boris offered. "We've got our or-" "Fuck the orders. Don't you see that these assholes will shoot us if we resist? What do you think Zhurov prefers more, losing this base and all the men here or keeping one operational squad?" Interjected Ponomarenko, the wounded military stalker. "Y-yes sir! Fuck the orders, sir!" Boris couldn't help but chuckle.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_211">
		<text>The air pulsated with wild energy and seemed to almost quiver in fear, just like the ground which rumbled like Borov's stomach. The sky was already starting to bleed, faint trickles of vermillion and scarlet streaks across the sky spreading like a beautiful flower - one that would mean death for many in due time. Lebedev looked at his old watch once and sighed as he adjusted the mechanical contraption's arms forwards. "Always 5 minutes slow no matter what I do," he grumbled silently. He cursed himself again and strode quickly towards Scar.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_212">
		<text>"The reason I've survived in this place as long as I have is that I always keep my word. You screw a client in this place, and you're pretty likely to find a knife in your back real quick," Sidorovich said matter-of-factly, reaching for a piece of greasy chicken that had been resting on a paper plate. "Anyway, just use common sense and treat your fellow stalkers with some respect and you should get along just fine out here."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_213">
		<text>"Wake up! Anthony, wake up!" The heavenly bliss of sleep was unceremoniously broken by the distant call roaring in my ear. With a trained but nonetheless reluctant motion I swung my body up from the sleeping bag. "What is it, Erwin?" I grumbled, assuming the most menacing expression they my tired self could do. But even as those words left my mouth, I could immediately sense that something was very off. The air was still, devoid of the distant hummings that always came from the Brain Scorcher.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_214">
		<text>Following the increase in emissions and the subsequent changing of the Zone's anomalous activity, the road to the Great Swamps opened up and certain individuals began moving in on what they hoped was an area of unharvested bounty and safe haven from authority. These people, dubbed the Renegades, soon got themselves into a turf war with the resident Clear Sky after committing several gruesome acts against fellow stalkers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_215">
		<text>The two Renegades on the sandbank, Bolt and Gurkha, had spotted a flesh sleeping in the reeds, and seeing a potential meal, began closing in. Bolt was so fixated on getting close enough to finish the pig with his knife that he did not notice Gurkha leaving behind. In the pitch-black darkness, a figure emerged from the water behind Gurkha, and a gloved hand stopped him from screaming. Bolt had gotten to the flesh and indulged in his sadistic slashing of the creature. Only when a knife slid into his back did he realize: it was too late.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_216">
		<text>Giorgi felt pain everywhere in his body. His feet ached, sharp cuts all over his legs and arms. He could see a faint spark ahead, and in the dim light Giorgi recognized a blade in his hand. It was a rusty old knife. Giorgi took a wobbly step towards the light, then another. What happened to him? He could not remember the last weeks, hell, barely anything from the last months. He remembered sneaking into the Zone, then joining Pitman's gang. Giorgi's head ached as he tried to push memories into the forefront, but all he found was blackness.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_217">
		<text>“Yob tvoyu matj! Friendly fire, you fucking idiots!” I shouted, wrenching his gun around to point at the approaching attackers. “We’re on the same side, blyadj! Bullets go that way!” To his credit, the Freedomer took my advice and let loose with more rounds. As I watched him firing, an enemy shot sparked off my shoulder armour. I whirled and zeroed in on the enemy, before putting a round in their gas mask eyepiece.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_218">
		<text>"Don't shoot, it's just a boar. Let's slip past quietly, we don't want to create any unwanted attention to ourselves. Who knows how many fucking Freedom, Duty, or worse: Mercs are out there. Just grab the rest of the loot and let's go. Now!"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_219">
		<text>The fire cracked silently as four Stalkers sat around it. The night was silent, only a small wind and the rustling of grass and leaves to fill the ears. One of the men spoke up suddenly: "Have you children heard the tale of the Monolith?" Hearing no replies, the man continued, "You see, in the center of the Zone, stands the Nuclear Power Plant. Many have tried to reach it, and all of them have failed. Their ambitions were mountains of artefacts and gold, and anything else their greedy minds could think of."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_220">
		<text>The rumors, quietly spoken aboard the Skadovsk, had proven true. Some long-forgotten administration building had been discovered by an explorer, one who had bolted at the sight, later claiming that the building felt "cursed" and that the red light shining above its doors was the ghastly eye of some monster as yet unknown to the Zone. "Superstitious nonsense to one who understands the Zone's ways," the stalker thought.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_221">
		<text>It was when he turned to leave the office that he realized- at some point the sounds of the storm had gone silent, much more quickly than should have been possible. The worry worming into his mind crystallized- why would a building have laid open for so long with none of the Zone's wildlife settling inside? Fear gripped his heart as he bolted back the way he came, boots clomping against the faded rug, only to skid to a stop as he came to the entrance. Only white concrete met his gaze. The entrance had vanished.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_222">
		<text>Tiger watched the mutated animals for a few seconds. He had kept himself alive this long on a single principle – the less trouble you cause, the less trouble you get – but the alternative to culling the four-eared creatures was a twenty-minute detour through dense vegetation. He had no special love for boars, and they were hardly endangered anyway. "Are you a fast shot?" he asked, swinging the Mosin off his back.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_223">
		<text>The Barrier had been here for as long as stalkers controlled the area. The military, loners, mercs and Duty had all manned its barricades at one time or another, but now it belonged to Freedom. It was an ominous place, the gnarly trees further up the cracked and cratered road standing as silent portents of what lay beyond: the impassable realm of the Brain Scorcher, overlooking the eastern Red Forest and blocking the way to Pripyat and the Zone's center. Past here, none but zombies and Monolith troops could survive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_224">
		<text>The roar of the rain became a dull thrum as he entered the building, his flashlight playing across dust-covered floors and furniture, the interior remarkably intact. Good- it meant that mutants hadn't made it a nest. Still, something itched at the back of his mind as he crept about, checking desks and cabinets, until he came upon what looked like an administrator's office. Paydirt! An object he'd never seen the likes of before hovered an arm's length above the stately oak desk, glowing softly, resembling two entwined rings of silver the width of his hand...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_225">
		<text>On the face of it, this was many a stalker's dream employment: a straightforward contract to escort some snotty but rich tourists around the countryside for a day or two, shoot a few animals and come back. Tiger knew better: Lugard's cannon looked impressive but it was a sportsman's weapon, carefully crafted and precisely adjusted. The Zone wasn't a place for such things – it was a place for loose tolerances, scuff-resistant finishes and generous magazine capacities. The notion of going to a place like the Red Forest seemed like trouble.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_226">
		<text>I came to the Zone trying to find a new artefact and strike it rich up north. I had no idea the Monolith would reactivate the Brain Scorcher and invade. I would give anything to leave this God forsaken place and return home — But now there was no way out. My only chance would be to fight my way to the Wish Granter. To make a last, desperate wish to end this nightmare, or die trying. What choice did I have?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_227">
		<text>I leaped up from cover and prepared to send another grenade at the Exo-Bandit, when I noticed he wasn’t moving; the Bandit was standing in one spot, his limbs quivering. My finger tightened on my trigger. Before I could go for the kill, the bandit jammed his AK’s barrel under the lip of his armored helmet, and blew his own head off. The rusted Exoskeleton jerked with the Bandit’s death spasms, and a thick red soup started oozing out from under the helmet; after a second, the Exo’s limbs went limp and the dead Bandit crumpled like a ragdoll.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_228">
		<text>All I remember was darkness and the cold creeping into me when I saw it... A bright light that filled me with warmth and spoke to me. "Come to me, you will gain what you deserve." Sometimes I see images of an older man with tears running down his face saying, "don't go we will be okay." Was that my father? Either way it does not matter. The Monolith must be defended from the heretics. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_229">
		<text>"This is General Tachenko, where are you? What are your coordinates? We will come and extract you, we just need a response God damnit!" General Tachenko banged his fist on the desk in anger. "We just lost an entire unit and now Freedom have complete control over Yanov!"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_230">
		<text>Collateral damage can be justified, if the gain outweighs the cost. How much do you think your faction members are worth?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_231">
		<text>I exist and I find it nauseating.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>